[Music]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se-
radio.net SC radio is brought to you by
the it computer society and by It
software Magazine online at computer.org
[Music]
software work OS is a modern identity
platform built for B2B SAS it provides
easy to use apis for authentication user
identity and complex Enterprise features
like SSO and skim provisioning work OS
is a dropin replacement for op zero and
supports up to 1 million monthly active
users for free it's perfect for B2B SAS
companies frustrated with high cost
opaque pricing and lack of Enterprise
capability supported by Legacy off
vendors today hundreds of high growth
scale UPS use work OS including ones you
probably know like versel webflow and
Loom check out work
os.com to learn more
hello everyone welcome to this episode
of software engineering radio this is
your host kin shringi and our guest
today is alel Soloman iel is CEO and
co-founder of flura dode luna.
simplifies and centralizes thirdparty
API management at skill e all has over a
decade of experience as a cyber security
engineer welcome to this show El
is there anything else you'd like to add
to your bio before we get started hey
kenin so first of all thanks for having
me excited to be here yeah I think I got
most of it covered coming from cyber
security more than a decade in that
landscape and now working on that cool
problem of apis so I'm in the API
landscape e luna. on your website says
and I use that in your introduction
simplifies and centralizes third party
API management and it's highlighted that
this is at scale so what's exactly new
apis have been around for a very long
time API management tools have been
around for a very long time and I'm sure
there a lot of API management companies
so what is the new problem that you're
trying to solve and why now yeah so
great question you got it correct I mean
apis has been out there for quite some
time but when we talking about apis
there's been a lot of focus on the API
provider side meaning that if I'm a
company and I have an API that I want to
expose out there for customers to use
then comes the API gateways and the API
management focus on the API provider
giving you with visibility governance
and controls into your Ingress traffic
meaning all the traffic that comes to
your API but there's two sides of it
right so there's the provider side but
there's also the consumer side and for
every API provider being provided
there's a consumer that that consumes
those apis and it's a known problem it's
not a a new one but it only takes rise
and scale as time goes by so now we're
seen basically a lot of companies
consuming much more apis and being
reliant on much more third party apis
than they used to in the past yeah I
agree with what you said a lot of the
discussions and toolings have focused on
the API provider even in terms of the
episodes we have done most of them have
been provider focused I would like to
point people though to uh episode 576 on
backend for front ends that did deal
with some of the challenges in consuming
apis but please
continue we are seeing an immense scale
in terms of consumption in recent years
and I think that that all proliferation
in llm apis and also openi actually gave
it a real boost but I think that now
there's a real focus of understanding
that consumption at scale
has costs related to them not only
financial cost but also costs in terms
of the maintenance that has to take
place and now it's like more in the
focus of engineering teams out there to
make sure that they have full control
visibility and the right tool set to
actually manage that consumption I think
that we may be focusing on something
that we pretty out there pioneering that
landscape but the problem is only ever
growing as the years scale let's talk a
little bit about the current AP
management companies what is it that
they focus on and what is it that you
mean that they're limited to the Ingress
traffic can you just start with some
examples of API management companies
yeah so we can name a few there's a few
cool ones out there once again for quite
some time from Kong to TA API moft those
are type of products that are mostly
focused on giving you controls so you
can rate limit the number API calls
being made to you as a provider so as a
provider but so when you consume it
isn't the consumer automatically
protected by that so that's the thing is
not I mean I can consume as much as I
want to but that API call will be made
to the provider and it will be processed
by the back end so it can decide maybe
tell me listen there's too many request
and then you're going to hit me with
that 429 back that response back but
it's still on his side as the provider
to limit consumption he will be the one
controls based on those API management
as we said to decide the way that he
want to regulates the traffic coming
into him and basically what lunar in
terms of position is saying listen you
need to have proper controls when it
comes to the client side you as a
consumer you need to know in advance how
many API calls will be made and how you
want to regulate that traffic based on
your business logic you shouldn't wait
on all of the time for the API provider
to give you with a response back you
should take control on your own limit
and regulate that rate of API calls
being made from your side and from your
perspective cash those API calls if
needed from the client side rather than
being API calls being cashed from the
server side of the provider what can API
providers themselves do to make the
adoption easier to solve some of the
problems that consumers are having is
there certain things that API providers
should adopt certain best practices that
have come out of this increase adoption
on the client side so it's a valid
question and I think that API providers
can do and a lot of them are doing a lot
to help their consumers API providers
are implementing caching throttling
mechanisms rate limits regulating the AP
traffic coming into their backend
environment on their own but we believe
that this problem needs to be shared and
managed by both the provider and the
consumer it's not enough for the
provider to take action because at that
point of time all of your customers are
making API calls it will take you some
kind of a processing time and processing
unit to decide whether you want to
digest and process that API call or not
we believe that the active controls
needs to take place from the client side
as well which is not on the API
providers to take ownership but rather
on the customers consuming that API so I
think that when we looking at the
broader concept of apis and API
consumption we need to think about the
active controls that needs to take place
both from the client side and from the
provider side or the API provider side
so that's an interesting example about
caching so you brought up two issues to
start with one is rate
limiting and to avoid making too many
API calls you said cash it on the client
side and not on the server side how does
one decide what to Cache whether it's on
the serice side or the client side so
excellent question and the answer is not
that simple I mean in order to
understand what is cachable we need to
drill deeper so you can cash API calls
on let's say two levels you can cash
base on the header you can see patterns
that kepts recurring in the header but
the thing that we understood is more
interesting as we've seen companies
implemented caching on their side is
that what is cashable will be within the
body of an API call a lot of the time so
think about it let's say that I'm making
an API call to a map service right a map
provider within the body or within the
query param will count the content of
what is the location that I want to make
a GE query upon so let's say I want a
query City New York
then that content will either be in the
body or sometimes within the query prum
those will be the type of things that is
important to keep track on and have
visibility in order to decide what's
cachable so let's say that I'm having
like a lot of API calls being made to
that service provider to that map
service provider I want to understand if
I'm making a lot of calls with City New
York or maybe a lot of calls with CD
Hong Kong and then I want to say those
will be the one cachable so instead of
making all of those API calls every time
I want to store some of them locally as
cash I want to give them a TTL I want to
give them like maybe a payload maximum
size and basically I don't want to go to
the API provider all the time so
actually by enforcing those type of
logic you can avoid going to the API
provider every time for every single API
call and make your backend
infrastructure much more resilient and
efficient and also cost effective when
it comes to the number of API calls
being made to the actual s provider that
type of logic is a type of project that
in order to enable it at first you got
to have full visibility to every API
call being made and also to the body and
the content of that API code only by
aggregating those data metrics you will
be able to understand what is cachable
what is not and how to enforce that
caching so that was a very specific
example and sounds like now that a lot
more organizations are adopting API so a
lot of these problems are becoming more
prevalent I do you have any numbers on
how much API adoption has increased over
the years and what is it now so in terms
of of API traffic in the internet out
there one of the recent surveys that
actually is not that updated I think
it's like three years ago something like
that from cloud flare talks about more
than 80% of internet traffic is API
calls that's a huge volume I think that
basically what it tells us that most of
the communication out there is being
made by API calls so the traffic is
immense keep in mind that the recent
blooming and maybe proliferation that
we're seeing across llm apis will only
get that Peak and volumes much bigger
because the natural progression is
obvious companies are having much less
functionality written on their own in
their back end and becoming much more
reliant on the third party apis they're
integrating with so as as day goes by
there's an Ever growing increase in the
number of API calls being made to EXT
providers and that Trend will only
increase over time that's the natural
progressions of SAS companies out there
from building something on their own to
relying on other platforms let's say I
want to now develop I can develop my
back end via versel so it's like a ther
right I can develop my back end on top
of super base but that actually gives
you the understanding that as companies
exporting or maybe like Outsourcing a
lot of their functionality it leaves you
remaining with with the Integrations
that you're integrating with so this is
like one of the the the most prevalent
trends that we're seeing in terms of
consuming traffic it varies actually
across Industries so with each industry
maybe let's give an example at the
beginning you had only just to name a
few HR type of apis out there the ATS
apis now there's like a dozens of them
it's in abundance so that scale in terms
of how many API providers can offer you
that same type of value proposition is
scaling over time so now I have a lot
more to choose from so in correlation a
lot more API calls being made to those
service providers I did read in one of
the links that you pointed out that I'll
put in the show notes that 90% of
organizations are now adopting apis and
sounds like two-thirds of them are using
some sort of API management software but
clearly as you're starting to explain
here that the API agement off it today
doesn't solve all the different problems
another number that I heard just
yesterday was that the unified payments
interface in India processes almost
2,400 transactions per second so that's
a very impressive number certainly
correlates with what you said about 80%
of internet traffic so I understand now
why we are talking about API management
from the consumer side and we've covered
a couple of examples of issues that are
unique to the consumer where you canot
rely on the provider to solve them for
you what are some of the other aspects
that
consumer API management has to deal with
that the provider doesn't or maybe you
can contrast it with some of the
problems that the provider deals with
that the consumer also has to
additionally at business Logic for yeah
so let's talk about what are the things
that me as an API consumer needs to take
care of or maybe needs to be aware of so
first of all and everything start with
visibility I need to have visibility
into my egress traffic I need to
understand before we get into that what
about just Discovery how do I even know
which is the right API to use Beyond
reading how to use the API let's say I
have two different providers for the
same functionality how do I choose
between them yeah so that's a lot to do
with reputation some API providers has
been out there and pretty stable and
what we called an API first companies
companies that are one of their main
value propositions is the API that
they're exposing other there those are
pretty known apis great the
communication not a lot of breaking
changes companies rely on on those apis
we know a lot of them I mean just to
name a few twio and stripe pretty known
household names but not all apis are
equal and some apis are poorly
documented some companies are are
exposing an API on their own but not
maintaining it that well and you can get
the indication of whether it's a poorly
documented API reading documentation
having look whether there's like a user
interface to keep track of API calls but
a lot of the time
you will start working with them and
only once you're working with them and
it's running in production at a scale
where you got to see the actual problems
started surfacing and I think that like
a cool distinction that I want the
audience to take uh into consideration
is between the apis that I want to use
and the apis that I'm being forced to
use and I'm not going to give specific
examples out there but just to give you
like the clear separation the API first
companies are apis that is being known I
mean developers love using them we love
using them but maybe you need to use
maybe like less documented less adequate
apis but you have to use those apis
because they're part of your value
proposition within your product and
you're relying on those apis now
problems begin to emerse and now
problems begin to emerge so how to
choose an API this is like a valid
question that reputation has has a lot
to do with but maybe even a more
interesting question is how do I get to
understand and choose as I'm consuming
apis in production whether I'm making
the right choice maybe I need to shift
between one API provider to the other
based on a specific uh business logic
maybe based on latency maybe based on
cost on a typical API call availability
error rate just to name a few so now
we're seeing companies taking a lot more
logic in their day-to-day operations
when choosing which API provider
basically like load balancing between
Alternatives when they want to cons
assume are getting like a specific value
proposition typically you write business
logic match to a specific API to the API
contract so now do you think that people
would want to code against multiple apis
or is there some understanding that
providers have to be more uniform in the
functionality and the contracts that
they
provide I love that question I mean that
question in order to answer it I think
that I don't think that it's on the
provider side to be like unified in the
way that that they're bringing the value
proposition it doesn't make sense in a
way because every company and every API
provider has its own type of value
that's what differentiate him it's up to
the consumer to decide which API you
want to consume and now we're getting to
the problem because I don't want to have
make a decision in real time I mean
hardcoded or maybe like manually on
which API providers to choose from the
ideal state that we've seen Enterprise
companies and sevy techy companies using
is basically making a unified facade so
that I want to have like a value so I'm
making an API call to a specific
provider and I'm going to give an actual
example in a second and I don't care
where that API call will be made to to
which API provider the only thing that
matters is based on my business logic
what will make most sense to my back end
and to the way that my product works in
terms of which API provider will process
that API call and to give you an actual
example we can actually see that parent
emerges as an actual so recently someone
describe it as an AI design pattern so
we actually seen that pattern emerge
with llm apis so there's like abundance
of API that will give you the ability to
like gen type of capabilities you have
barred by Google and you have chat GPT
by open Ai and you have like the open
source llms and you have anthropic and
you have a lot of them they're not equal
in terms of cost in terms of accuracy
when you're talking about the prompt
that I'm going to send and the response
I'm going to get back and now begins
like the hard type of things to take
into consideration now companies need to
think of okay where should I make that
API call to should I always make it to C
GPT C GPT 4 in particular which is
highly expensive but like known to be
accurate or maybe I need to
differentiate maybe some customers or
VIP customers those those customers I
will shift that prompt to chat GPT for
but for the last prioritized API calls I
will shift them to one of the open
source or maybe to the more to the less
expensive API providers so now you're
getting like that proxy logic in the
middle of saying for each every API call
that I'm going to make there will be a
business logic that can be enforced
before making that actual API call to
the provider based on cost based on
resilience based on availability and
like the use cases are numerous I mean
every company and their own type of
logic to take to take place but this is
now a thing that companies needs to
think about when implementing
Integrations and running those
Integrations in real time and and large
scale so a couple of follow-up questions
on that what you said assumes that the
API is usage based what about
subscription based apis what are you
observing is it mostly usage based so
the API economy is is wide and I can say
how it's uh divided between API calls
usage based type of API calls tiers some
of apis are actually free a lot of like
the the known ones I can say that
there's like specific problems
associated with each and every business
model so for example in the usage based
type of model how do I know in advance
how many API calls will be made and what
would be the pricing at the end of the
month so visibility and correlation to
cost is a big thing that that it's
missing out there for a lot of the API
provider side for the tier-based apis as
you mentioned we've getting it from
customers saying listen I don't know
whether the tier that I'm using is the
right tier maybe I consuming less than
what I thought I need to like degrade to
a lower tier maybe I need to merge
between two teams that consuming
different tiers but they can be merged
to the same API provider with the same
key because they will be under the same
quot so every type of business model com
with his own type of problems I will say
that actually we've seen that some of
the most problematic apis that we've
held companies optimize and manage are
apis that are free basically or low cost
those are sometimes the apis that you
have to to use and not the ones that you
choose to do so voluntarily so if it is
usage based as you did mention or even
if it's subscription based with multiple
tiers as you mentioned you don't really
necessarily have ibility right away into
what the cost is going to be or do you
are you saying that teams are starting
to project what that cost will be based
on how many apis are getting used so in
the differentiation that we did a few
minutes ago between API first companies
and companies are not API first we've
seen that the API first companies can
offer you with a panel that gives you
the understanding of how much you
consuming that cost even predictions I
mean look at open AI look at their user
panel and and you'll see that
correlation not all apis are open Ai
apis and as I said the last Advanced the
last API first step of companies will
not give you that visibility so it's up
to you to build that visibility it's up
to you to aggregate those metrics and
data points and keep track on those API
calls to understand what will be the
cost and this is the thing not only from
the cost perspective but think about it
I mean you have so much visibility and
understanding into your in traffic the
API you providing with what about your
ESS traffic I mean how many companies
are keeping track of how many API calls
being made from their back end from
distributed back end of multiple
services this is a thing that is both a
problem for in in terms of cost that as
re claim and try to convey will only
grow over time become one of the most
problematic issues in Productions out
there but it's also a problem that has
to do with purely engineering I mean if
you're not keeping track of the number
API calls being made and the health
check of those API Integrations then how
will you be aware in advance of what
needs to be taking place I mean how do
you you know which type of management
and resilience implementations you need
to build for each and every API
integration so visibility is a thing
that has to do with cost but also in
terms of resilience and efficiency of
your back end as well and also in terms
of SLA right I mean you're providing
with SLA to your customers that a lot of
the time is being Reliant on those third
party Integrations so SLA also has to do
with visibility I'd like to point
listeners to episode
550 Mike Fuller and Jr storment on cloud
finops Financial operations so since
this certainly starting to be an area
that people need to focus on as elel you
mentioned how do they even know how many
API calls they're making what their slas
are to their customers but also to track
spending lot of companies and you
certainly mentioned open AI has usage
information how do people consume that
let's say you you have that information
you have all this data you collect it at
the end of a certain period of time and
then you use it to refine your policies
or is there another methodology people
adopt or you recommend so I think that
the way that companies do it is actually
correlating to the stage of of the
implementation that they've built and
I'll explain
talking with many customers about their
problem with API consumption here at
lunard Dev we understood that there's
like layers in terms of let's call it an
evolution of middleware right so there's
like three layers that we have
identified and at the beginning we've
seen that the first layer is basically
like the the layer that we're all aware
of I'm a developer part of the
application uh development team I'm the
one responsible of integrating with a
third party API if something goes down
or problematic with that API it's up to
me to fix it and that will be most of
the time adoc fixes so visibility I'm
just going to implement basic visibility
maybe I'm going to connect it connect it
to an APM like my data dog or my New
Relic or maybe I don't know if grafana
but that will give you just like the
basic understanding of of traffic once
again not the full content of a payload
within an API call but just like the
basic stuff but as we've seen companies
scale over time that actually become a
more centralized problem so now we've
seen actually companies dedicating teams
mostly the integration team to build
some kind of a a managed solution out
there we call it a stateless middleware
at that point of time we've seen that
companies are now adding the ability to
basically edit request and responses so
now visibility be becomes to be even
better now you can collect metrics and
traces now maybe it's the just the very
very beginning of of a observability now
we can actually sometimes tag API calls
and you can build more sophisticated
middleware than just throttling you talk
about it being stateless as compared to
stateful that remembers what all does it
remember nice that's what we call the
holy grade this is like the third layer
this is Enterprise grade type of API
middleware basically saying that not all
problems can be solved by wrapping up
code or by adding code on top of your
existing application some problems needs
to have unified orchestration between
them it means that you need to have a
dedicated service we call it like the
egress service that will hold a state
between multiple Services consuming
let's say the same API quota I'm going
to give an actual example we've seen one
of our customers consuming the same API
provider not going name because it
doesn't matter which API but it
consumate both from Stag and production
stag in a production are sharing the
same API key now they have like a
limited quarter right I mean this is
like the number of API calls you can
make in a specific time frame might it
be a year a day a month or a week now
we're seeing that they want to
prioritize calls between production and
staging because production is of course
obviously much more important than
staging so now you need to shift the
traffic or maybe regulate the traffic
coming to the same API provider so the
80% for example of the traffic will come
from staging and only 20% will come from
from production sorry and and 20% will
come from staging and now you can add
more complexity on top of it like
besides deciding which what would be the
balance between two Services how do you
manage like that remaining of a quota if
you didn't reach to that Peak that
spillover all of those logic that needs
to take place cannot be solved by just
implementing additional code there needs
to be a shared state that understand the
current let's say quota in that in that
example between different environments
some even like different customers
different tenants and decide based on
your logic how to regulate that traffic
and this is just to give you one example
take that concept and now make it like
even on a higher level think about the
the ability to regulate traffic and the
side traffic between different regions
for example because our implementation
that ESS proxy is a proxy then you also
need to Lo balance and scale that proxy
on its own so that if one proxy is being
let's say bounded by the number of API
CS that it can process you need to have
another scaling horizontally to another
API proxy another egress proxy basically
what I'm trying to say is that for the
complex tyer problems that has to do
with usage at scale this is when we've
seen companies and once again a lot of
them has been Enterprise companies or
companies that's serving Enterprise
customers are building or trying to
build their own dedic ated type of
egress middleware that has a shared
state to it because this is the way to
go and this is the natural progression
of companies that we've seen from
basically no middleware just wrap things
in code to actually a stateless
middleware being implemented a lot of
the time by integration team to that
Holy Grail of a dedicated egress service
a stateful type of service type of
middleware that a lot of the time is
under responsibility of the platform
team or the infro team sometimes it's
like a dedicated task force from the R&D
but this is like the way that we've seen
at lunar basically what we're doing is
providing you with a production grade
ready Enterprise type of service we're
saying in that build versus by dilemma
we're like that fine grained type of
tool that will give you all of that both
visibility and controls to your traffic
at scale between different Services
between different distributed
environment this is what lunar is set up
for to actually build and solve as an
Ever growing type of problem
hey innovators the i e computer
society's door is wide open for your
next big idea with the emerging Tech
grants program dream big and you can
land funding between 25 and 50k jump on
this chance at our website computer.org
dgrs that's computer.org
dgrs before we get a little bit into
more details of solutions yeah I wanted
to cover what any other areas of issues
that clients need to deal with maybe
let's talk about security next and what
is it that one needs to do on the
consumer side over and Beyond what the
provider is taking care of cool that's
stock security speaking with customers
so security is like an emerging thing
and basically once again there's been a
lot of focus on API Security on the
Ingress side helping the API providers
but basically when it comes to consuming
third party apis this is like a No Man's
Land basically like saying that you
trust the integration that that you're
working with I mean once you've done the
integration you're not thinking a lot
about the data that is being transmitted
outside via an API calls and this is a
potential security breach on its own so
I think that the latest oasp in API
security that actually released like
just a few months ago is strictly saying
unsafe API consumption like in those
words basically saying that if the API
provider has been breached then it's a
supply chain kind of attack so that II
provider is now being compromised and
you can tag it as malicious so now
you're making an API code and that
provider will tell you listen you want
me to give you data from that specific
API endpoint cool how about redirecting
here and that redirection who's checking
that redirection whether it's a
malicious endpoint or not so basically
the answer is that no one at the moment
no one is checking all of those I mean
where the API provider is deciding to
redirect you and that can be a security
breach as I said on its own on another
perspective how about piis and tokens
and all of those data that can be shared
and exposed to the API provider the not
a lot of companies are keeping track and
auditing which piis has been sent and
leaked outside and it's also become to
be a thing so this is another aspect
that need needs to have proper
management and controls on top of it it
doesn't just ends with having visibility
which is once again a big thing you need
to have that proper visibility and
auditing it also has to do with controls
I mean once you're understanding that
maybe something is malicious or that you
do not want to make that API call maybe
you don't want to even get that API
response back you need to have some kind
of mitigation layer in between as we've
seen it like with the egress proxy that
proxy in the middle they will take an
API request an API response and have
some kind of a ruling Logic on top of it
before processing or making that API
call to the provider or back to the back
end of the consumer side so egress
traffic and the security of egas traffic
is also something that we've seen
companies talk with us about and become
to be a thing we can also talk about
authentication who's managing
authentication I mean authentication can
be managed from that proxy side of
things or not right so this is another
thing that has to do with security and
once again the thing that I want to
maybe convey our listeners is that think
about your eess traffic think about how
much visibility you have think about the
proper controls that reinforcing on top
of that traffic that can come with
security cost and efficiency we're
talking about the engineer side of
things so certainly those issues all in
both the development aspects and
monitoring aspects starting with Ure
Shing you're relying on API first
companies and their documentation for
Discovery making sure that at runtime
you're operationalizing tracking of up
times and slas number of ESS traffics
how the costs are changing you're
definitely orchestrating apis but now
you're potentially orchestrating them
across multiple API providers you're
doing load balancing you're dealing with
throttling on the provider side you're
potentially caching queries caching API
calls on the client side as well for
optimal cost you're having to deal with
security aspects and certainly
authentication at scill so I get it it's
quite a number of things to handle and
you started to talk about Bill versus
buy if I do want to build though and I
don't want to build all of it what is
available in the market today what are
the technology pieces that I can buy to
further build my solution cool so
basically what we've implied along the
conversation is that you need to have a
proxy in the middle you can call that
proxy an API proxy right something a lot
of time you can dub it as a reverse
proxy so that between your back end and
the API providers there will be some
kind of aay in between there will count
Matrix give you that visibility that
we're talking about that needed
visibility and also the controls only
request and on response I mean before
API call being made outside and before
it comes back keep in mind that that
control needs to have before the API
call will be encrypted because as we
talked about the actual data that is
interesting to take controls upon will
be within a dead body of an API call so
you need to look at the traffic before
encryption in order to make sense out of
it and at the moment the things that you
need to do when you're building it on
your own is take a proxy either build it
on your own or take some kind of an open
source proxy
and build that layer on top of it but it
doesn't stop there you don't need just
to build that proxy that will handle API
request you need to intercept the
traffic and now in today's environment
it's a distributed environment there's a
lot of as we said a lot of services a
lot of clusters how do you intercept
that traffic and now once you
intercepted that traffic you need to
think about the next phase how do you
prevent it from that proxy to be a
single point of failure how how do you
manage availability so if one proxy goes
down one will come up how do you manage
scale so that you want to load balance
between different proxies as they scale
and as your API consumption scale how do
you keep track of low latency because
some of the companies that are consuming
apis need to have like a really low
latency in terms of meeting their slas
so how do you keep track that no adeny
will be added how do you endure Peak
traffic volumes so that if I don't know
let's give an example of a e-commerce
type of company that serving a lot of
customers out there and now it's subber
Monday or Black Friday how do you manage
that Peak traffic in terms of volue of
API calls so everything to have when
you're thinking about implementing or
building something on your own you need
to think about that autoscale
infrastructure of those proxies you need
to think about fail safe fail tolerance
High availability you need to think
about how I making sure that there's no
impact in terms of latency how do I
Endure Peak traffic and another thing to
keep in mind is that how do I make sure
that the infrastructure that I've built
on top of that proxy is configurable
because it doesn't make sense to just
build it for one team once you've built
it you need to think about the other
team is in your organization they will
need to use that proxy so I'm making
sure that they can actually have
configurable type of logic within that
proxy so that they can actually answer
different needs and as we've seen with
companies companies are now consuming
dozens if not hundreds of apis in
production so you need to think about
the concept of how you can do reuse of
those logic and not build everything
from the get-go for each and every new
type of integration that will take place
so if you're thinking about building
something on your own that eras
controller as we say you need to think
about scale latency configurability and
measuring the impact of your operations
okay that's quite a lot of work and what
I found interesting is that lunar is
actually open source so I'd certainly
like to in the next section talk a
little bit more in how exactly lunar has
enhanced the gross proxy to handle these
problems yeah we're open source because
we believe that it's the way to go from
a few points first of all is as follows
we need to build trust with our
community right so no better way of
saying listen this is the code and you
can look at the code and it's not a
blackbox I mean we understand in order
to have a proxy that sits in the middle
between your back end and the API calls
that you're making those business
critical apis you need to have trust
with our solution so part of that trust
will be open source another thing that
we understood why it needs to be open
sourced is because you need to know that
that proxy is configurable so you can
add on top of it so if you want to take
that proxy and build your specific logic
on top of it you can do so because it's
configurable so this is another thing
that is associated with open source and
maybe the third thing about open source
and the reason that we decide to go open
source is that because that problem that
we trying to solve of managing and
optimizing ESS traffic your third party
API consumption it's really a
Distributive problem there's no way in
hell that we can answer all of the needs
for all of those companies out there
consuming millions of apis with their
own type of business bu logic it will be
pretentious of saying that we can do so
but what we can do is build a platform
that companies can build on top of that
platform so that that aggregated data
that the community will build will be
something that is sharable and basically
we can say like to the next customer
that will come and use lunar and this is
what we're doing at the moment is listen
you're consuming API X we know that apix
is problematic but we've seen other
companies implemented caching with those
cash keys and values to solve a problem
associated with cost or like high
latency so this is like another thing
about saying like the community is part
of building that product and this is
like another aspect of why that product
needs to be open sourced thanks for the
introduction on the lunar dodev as an
open source and your intention and your
goal and vision for it to be used as a
platform could you start with explaining
how somebody would actually configure
the ESS proxy for their use yeah for
sure the beginning is by installing the
solution and the solution as we said is
built up out of two components you got
the egress proxy or the egress
controller as we call it and you have
the interceptors so interceptors are
those thin components that sits on the
backand side on a service level or on
the cluster level that is sole purpose
is actually capturing API traffic before
encryption and only for the selective
type of AP API calls that our customers
want to manage those will be wired via
the egress proxy within the egress proxy
the customers and the users will be able
to Define policies before the API call
actually being made to the SAS provider
and upon a response getting back from
that SAS provider so the thing that
actually is taking form is the ability
to decouple between the maintenance code
of that API integration and the actual
integration so if up until now
developers were to build on top of their
code and maintain their own type of
middleware implementation such as
cashing and throttling now they can do
it as a policy the way that it works
within the system is that once you're
seeing all of the API traffic that ESS
traffic you can't Define policies at the
moment we've published a few policies we
call them building blocks right so you
have a policy of rewi policy of cashing
a policy of load balancing of traffic
those type of policies are building
blocks and customers can configure
pretty much basically everything that
they want to do so I'll give you like a
stct example if you want to Define
client side throttling the thing that
you want to Define based on the way that
you're consuming that type of API
provider is let's say how many allowed
requests can I make in a specific time
window so I want to Define as a user as
a developer I want to define the time
window of that throttling I want to
define the number of requests I want to
define the status code by which a
trigger will be made whether it be a 429
for example of too many requests if you
want to do class ey throttling you want
to do it once you're going to hit pick
traffic he seing those 429s from the
provider so all of those things are
configurable on top of a policy another
example is talking about caching you
want to Define caching so it will give
you the ability to actually Define rules
for that caching for example what will
be the cash Keys what will be the T L of
those cash Keys what will be the max
size of the caching and for storing each
cached call so this is the type of
configurable infrastructure that we're
allowing our developers to build on top
of the system Step One is using those
building blocks step two of the system
which we're working on at the moment
assuming it will be released by the time
the podcast will be released is what we
call chains or flows which means that
you can actually chain between different
policies so if you want to do throttling
with a que a prioritize queue you want
to chain between re rise and alerts and
all of those complex logic you will be
able to do so on your own just like as a
simple drag and drop type of flow so is
that sufficient it's configuration are
cases where clients actually have to
extend the proxy with code that's an
excellent question the answer is yes and
because we understand that the platform
needs to be extended by our developers
then we able to allow so along 2024
somewhere along the road map we are
planning on making the platform fully
extendable so once again at that point
of time you can Define between policies
the next phase will be chaining of those
policies and the third stage will be
actually extending it with your own code
so that you can actually write
additional policies tailor specific to
your use cases so we've seeing that in
some use cases you need to Define maybe
a particular policy or maybe a
particular type of plugin that will Feit
your needs and this is the way that the
system will be flexible and extendable
along the way by the way part of the
reason that we're able to do so is
because the egress proxy has been built
upon AJ proxy which has an extendability
to it I see so the ESS proxy that you
mentioned built on top of H proxy you
earlier talked about the key things that
anybody building the proxy and I guess
lunar has had to consider and even more
because you're offering it as a platform
is the scale the configurability the
latency operations and maybe there's
more can you just pick a couple and
explain some of the challenges you've
had to face in doing that definitely I
think that when thinking about either
implementing or building your own type
of egress controller to manage your
outgoing API traffic you need to think
about what what it takes to be
production grade ready and by production
grade ready I'm referring to the ability
to scale that proxy that proxy can
withhold only up until a certain amount
of API calls being made concurrently and
with each policy that will take place on
API calls there will be like an added
latency so you need to understand how
you can actually make that proxy as a
scalable type of infrastructure so you
can actually load balance between
different proxies so you can actually
distribute the proxies across for
example zones or regions so that you
have the ability to have high
availability because if one proxy will
go down another proxy will kick off so
those are the type of production great
considerations that we've seen companies
really need to take care of this is like
part of the reason why decided to go for
that challenge and build it on our own
because we've seen a need to actually
build something that is like production
grade scalable as it takes this is like
one aspect of consideration another one
is thinking about latency we know that
some companies using API providers and
really sensitive in terms of the latency
that it takes to make an API call and
get that response back so you need to
think that if you're having a proxy in
the middle how much added latency I made
to each and every API call it need to
make sense it needs to make it efficient
to make that call being transferred via
a proxy and not directly so you need to
think about latency and measure it and
making sure that it's low as possible
for example at lunar we were
benchmarking a latency on a constant
basis I can say that in the P95 we're
adding up to four milliseconds of
latency which is kind of insignificant
but this something that needs to be
taken care of this is like a segue to
another way of thinking of what you need
to do when building your own type of
erress controller which will be
measuring the actual impact of your AP
operations upon that egress traffic you
need to understand what has happened
before the API proxy to control and
after so you need to measure that impact
you need to Define thresholds let's say
for example you want to Define a
threshold of what will be the right
point in time where another for example
proxy will take place or that I'm going
to stop some API calls from being made
because I'm don't want to hit those 429s
so threshold and alert of threshold is
something that needs to be considered as
well and I'll will say that the last
thing which actually reverts to the
question that we've talked about before
is the configurability and the
extendability of the platform as we've
seen companies consume dozens if not
hundreds of apis and you need to think
about a platform that can be extended
and configurable to each and every type
of API provider and not just be like
that Standalone type of solution that
it's not configurable and it's like
almost like hardcoded so this is like
another configuration we building when
you're thinking about building an igress
type of an NE controller so what are the
apis that lunar provides your consumers
so that they can get visibility into how
your lunar is helping how the eess proxy
is helping so the way that we're
reflecting those type of data and
controls to our customers is first of
all by saying visibility you need to
have full visibility in real time of all
of your API traffic ESS API traffic so
the first phase of the product upon
installation once you've install the
proxy and the interceptors will be the
discovery phase so you're get that full
discovery which will give you visibility
in real time to the API you're consuming
all the way to the API endpoint and then
on top of it we can give you with
substantial data to be ried upon the
error rate even for a specific provider
of a specific endpoint the number of API
calls being made when was that last time
that you communicated with an API and
made an API call the latency that is
being measured by an API call for a
specific Prov
all of those can be under the umbrella
of saying this is like the discovery
phase this is full visibility on top of
visibility because you can define those
thresholds you can understand okay now
I'm seeing problems within my IP
Integrations now I'm seeing that for
specific API Integrations I'm hitting
with a lot of 429s so once you will see
it within the system you will have the
actual ability to Define what we called
as we said a policy so visibility
detection of problems or inefficiencies
and then the right plugin you might
Define your plugin on your own or you're
getting suggestions of what will be the
adequate plug-in to deploy to solve that
particular need and that's the way that
we actually show you after you enforce
in a policy what was the impact of that
policy being enforced what happened
before lunar and after lunar was making
its magic with the ESS controller how
can uh listeners contact you and if you
wanted to say anything more about the
open source nature of lunar them yeah so
let's start with the open source part
lunar is open source you can actually
today either go to our repo download the
proxy start using it the proxy the
interceptors have a go edit or you can
connect from the UI which is available
from our website and start getting all
of that visibility and enforcement of
policies so this is like one of the as
we talked about during our podcast
episode this is one of the key things
that lunar isol about being out there
for the community the manag version of
lunar is the thing that we're going to
charge upon and this is something that
is also being available to upgrade from
the UI and in terms of contact with me
please do please feel free you can
either contact me via website via
LinkedIn Twitter I mean we're available
out there Discord you name it we're out
there we want to hear you we want to
help you out dealing with your API
traffic problems just give me a shout
out and talk to me so I'll reach out out
to you for your Discord handle and
LinkedIn contact and we can put that in
the show notes Perfect all right thank
you so much alel is there anything else
you'd like to add before we end today
thank you so much for the opportunity it
was a pleasure and yeah let's optimize
API traffic thank
you thanks for listening to SC radio an
educational program brought to you by I
software magazine for more about the
podcast including other episodes visit
our website at se-
radio.net to provide feedback you can
comment on each episode on the website
or reach us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter
or through our slack Channel at
seo. slack.com you can also email us at
team
e-r. this and all other episodes of SC
radio is licensed under creative
comments license
2.5 thanks for listening